MATHEW HUUSKO V

SUMMARY

Software. Software.

I work full time engineering software at Black Duck Software. I wear a small hat at a big house at the intersection of open-source and enterprise. I take pride in being part of an effort to spread the appropriate use of open-source (something I couldn't live without) to individuals and large companies to help creative people collaborate. I'm the engineering half of Illuminated Core Inc. As does my partner, Kevin Thompson, I wear a few different hats in order to make sure that what we produce is a meaningful distraction. I like being entertained, I like making software for entertainment, and I like it when that software entertains people.

I also create software independently, without a special title (or desk usually). I'm the mad hatter - I make and wear all the hats, from invention and concept creation to experience and interface design to creation of visual assets to engineering. I'm on a mission to do away with the traditional button/menu organized, cursor controlled, keyboard shortcut enhanced, desktop experience, and my target is Mac OS X.

EXPERIENCE

Black Duck Software

09 / 2013 - Present

Software (User Interface) Engineer

Black Duck Software is working on a new cloud-based unification of its classic product line of open source code search, code security and license analysis, and management at the enterprise level. I am part of the team developing this new platform, currently contributing mostly to the user-facing Backbone web application, having started as an intern working on the Java Spring backend.

Illuminated Core Inc. 06 / 2012 - Present

Co-Founder/CTO, Software Engineer Lead

I am currently working closely with co-founder and user experience/graphic design lead Kevin Thompson (http://www.linkedin.com/in/kevinpthompson) on a number of game and media collaborations. We are particularly proud of our most recent release, the game Buzz Kill. It's an awesome classic-arcade-game-influenced-CIA-drone-bee-shoot-'em-up adventure, which comes in both mouse controlled and Leap Motion interfaced flavors.

Self Employed 06 / 2010 - Present

Software Creator

For about four years I've been creating software non-stop. Some of my work never leaves my computer, but most of it I either open source, or polish up for distribution - browsing my Github and personal website would give you a pretty good look at these projects. Currently I'm most focused on a series of extensions to Mac OS X that replace existing cursor, keyboard, and menu based interactions with multitouch trackpad driven (what I consider deferred-touch) gesture based interactions. Two of the pieces in the series are completed, which cover application switching, and launching. The third in the series, a trackpad driven virtual keyboard, is in early stages of development.

Black Duck Software 06 / 2013 - 09 / 2013

Worked on a Java adapter library for common source control managements systems (Git, SVN, Perforce) as part of an (currently private, beta) enterprise targeted open source code analysis and management product. Also made significant contributions to bug fixes and integration/regression testing surrounding this product.

Phillips Exeter Academy

09 / 2010 - 06 / 2013

Student

I graduated with high-honors after three trying years of consistent high academic performance, while in parallel starting my career as a software creator (going from "System.out.println()" to interning at Microsoft in a little more than a year).

Microsoft 07 / 2012 - 09 / 2012

Software Development Engineer Intern

I interned for the summer as a development engineer on the SAMM team working on the App-V (Application Virtualization) product as a part of Microsoft's Desktop Optimization Package. I independently designed, developed, and delivered a Window Communication Foundation web service and accompanying Windows 8 (at that time, "Metro") client app for reporting usage statistics for applications being used by virtualized client sets, to support the then beta release of App-V 5.0.

Measured Progress

06 / 2011 - 08 / 2011

Assistant Software Developer

I interned for the summer as an assistant software developer, working on writing unit/integration tests for a large scale web service which handles reporting student, school, and district level results of U.S. state-specific standardized testing (e.g. MCAS, NECAP). I also spent some time working alongside quality assurance to reduce bugs in the front facing web client backed by this service.

SKILLS		
JavaScript	HTML	
Java	Ruby	
Perl	C++	
Python	SQL	
Dart	Less	
WCF Services	Entity Framework	
PHP		
	Java Perl Python Dart WCF Services	

EDUCATION

Phillips Exeter Academy

2010 - 2013

High School , General/Computer Science

HONORS

Phillips Exeter Academy 2012 "Upper" Computer Science Award (One of four given) Phillips Exeter Academy 2013

department" (One of one given)		
INTERESTS		
software development, human-computer relationships, user interface design, music		
LANGUAGES		

Italian (Elementary proficiency)

"Special" Computer Science Award, "acknowledging significant personal achievement and contribution to the

 $Spanish \,\, (\, {\tt Limited \, working \, proficiency}\,)$

 $English \ ($ Native or bilingual proficiency)